AP/ACCOUNTING & HR GENERALIST

Summar

A Customer Service and Credit & Collections expert that has directly managed numerous clients and work groups in creating sustainable business relationships and continuous improvement business solutions, which has led to millions of dollars in revenue/sales. A highly motivated and accomplished CSR, with over seven years of direct client/customer management experience. Skills

- MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint,
- Proficient in SAP, AS400, Accpac, JD Edwards, Autoscribe, Cash Application, Pos Partners, EC Zone, Get Paid, InstaPay, Retail Link, QuickBooks and Aceva (Collection Software)
- Tracking Budget Expenses, Attention to Detail, Thoroughness, Organization, Analyzing Information, Accounting & Vendor Relationships
- Excellent Customer Service, Interpersonal, & Multitasking skills

Experience

AP/Accounting & HR Generalist

Raleigh, NC Harness / Feb 2017 to Current

- Ensured accurate, timely accounting and thorough understanding of all financial information monthly, quarterly and year-end closings, including bank compliance and taxation issues.
- Monitored accuracy and timely processing of payment transactions.
- Reconciles processed work by verifying entries and comparing system reports to balances.
- Recording entries; charge expenses to accounts and cost centers by analyzing invoice/expense reports.
- Payment to vendors by monitoring discount opportunities; verifying federal id numbers; scheduling and preparing checks; resolving purchase order, contract, invoice, or payment discrepancies and documentation; insuring credit is received for outstanding memos; issuing stoppayments or purchase order amendments.
- Payment to employees by receiving and verifying expense reports and requests for advances; preparing checks.
- Maintaining accounting ledgers by verifying and posting account transactions.
- Verify vendor accounts by reconciling monthly statements and related transactions.
- Back up for A/P and Billing personnel.
- Processing employees, updating records, improving employee retention levels, employee relations, enforcing safety and health policies.

AR Accountant

North Olmsted, OH Tempur Sealy International, Inc / Aug 2015 to Feb 2017

- Maintained a collection/deduction resolution portfolio on Accpac, including collection calls, faxes, and e-mail correspondence.
- Responsible for cash application, adjustments for all company divisions both retail and mass merchant accounts, approximately \$2.5 million dollars in receivables per month.
- Responsible for the release of orders, generating credit memos, and miscellaneous bills on Accpac.
- Analyzed, planned, and reported out to management status of portfolio under my responsibility.
- In charge of in house deposit, approving credit files, pulling D&B reports and ordering office supplies.
- Back up for A/P and Billing personnel.

Store Manager

Plymouth, IN Firstsource Solutions / Jul 2014 to Aug 2015

- Responsible for managing the operation on the store.
- This includes managing the accounts receivable, accounts payable, purchasing, production, marketing and customer service daily operations
 of the store.
- Work directly with manufacturing process to ensure orders, quality and commit ship dates are satisfied.
- Work directly with suppliers on logistics and shipment arrangement for local/domestic shipments.

Customer Service Representative

Fort Worth, TX Kroger / Aug 2010 to Jul 2014

- Responsible for managing customer progress payment orders.
- YD volume of \$31 million and three month moving average of \$11 million.
- Responsible for managing regional accounts.
- This includes resolving credit issues, order and shipment discrepancies.
- · Work directly with manufacturing to ensure orders and commit ship dates are satisfied.
- Work directly with clients on logistics and shipment arrangement for domestic and international shipments.

Accounts Receivable/Cash Application Specialist

City, STATE SPX FLOW TECHNOLOGIES / Jan 2008 to Aug 2010

- Analyzed, planned, and reported out to management status of portfolio under my responsibility.
- In charge of in house deposit, approving credit files, pulling D&B reports and ordering office supplies.
- Maintained a collection/deduction resolution portfolio on Aceva, including collection calls, faxes, and e-mail correspondence.

- Responsible for cash application, adjustments for Dehydration/Hankison, Canada and Dollinger Division, approximately \$10 million dollars in receivables per month.
- Responsible the release of orders, generating credit memos, and miscellaneous bills on AS400 and SAP.

Credit and Collections Representative

City, STATE EMERSON ELECTRIC / May 2005 to Jan 2008

- Analyzed, planned, and reported out to management status of portfolio under my responsibility.
- Maintained a collection/deduction resolution portfolio on Aceva, including collection calls, faxes, and e-mail correspondence.
- Responsible for West Coast, Florida, Georgia, Canada, and International Accounts with an average portfolio size of \$5 million (successfully reduced from \$12 million).
- Responsible for the release of orders, generating credit memos, and miscellaneous bills on AS400.

General Production Worker

City, STATE SPHERION TEMPORARY SERVICES / Jan 2005 to May 2005

- Hired as temporary employee to work in the production line.
- After four months hired as a core employee and promoted to Credit & Collections Representative.

Education and Training

 $Associates: Arts \ Business \ Administration \ COLLEGE \ OF \ CENTRAL \ FLORIDA \ December \ 2015 \ City \ , \ State \ Arts \ Business \ Administration \ 3.8 \ Bachelor: Accounting \ RASMUSSEN \ COLLEGE \ December \ 2015 \ City \ , \ State \ Accounting \ 3.3$

Languages

Proficient in Spanish with reading and writing ability

Skills

Accounting, accounts payable, accounts receivable, Accpac, A/P, AS400, Attention to Detail, Billing, Budget, Interpersonal, Credit, clients, Excellent Customer Service, customer service, documentation, e-mail, employee relations, expense reports, faxes, financial, JD Edwards, logistics, managing, manufacturing process, marketing, Excel, PowerPoint, MS Word, Multitasking, ordering office supplies, personnel, policies, Pos, progress, purchasing, quality, QuickBooks, reading, receiving, reconciling, Recording, Retail, safety, SAP, scheduling, Proficient in Spanish, yearend

Additional Information

• Awards and Accomplishments *Honors Student *Dean's List